Nabil Shahid



nabil110176@gmail.com

+92-347-7363136

Software developer having 5+ years of experience solving business critical problems through technology. Experienced in architecting, developing and maintaining small to large scale software systems. Advocate of making processes efficient through integration of right tools and automations. Experienced working both in teams and independently. Takes ownership of work and also contribute to the growth of the team.

Skills

During my experience as a Software Developer, I have worked closely with a number of technologies while working on front end views, back end APIs, databases, asynchronous processing, setting up CI/CD pipelines, configuring servers, application monitoring etc.

Among all, I consider myself proficient at working with the following technologies:

- Programming Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript, Python
- Front End: VueJS, Vuex, React, Redux, Angular, Webpack, Vite, Gulp, Babel, HTML, CSS, SASS, Tailwind.
- Back End: NodeJS, NestJS, ExpressJS, Flask, FastAPI, Celery, AWS SQS, SQLAlchemy, Mongoose
- Database: SQL, PostgresSQL, MSSQL, MongoDB, Google Firestore.
- Serverless: AWS Lambdas, Google Cloud Functions.
- Source Control Management: Git.
- CI/CD: Gitlab Pipelines, Github Actions, AWS Code pipeline.
- Monitoring Tools: Datadog, Sentry, AWS Cloudwatch.
- Testing: Jest, React Testing Library, Vue Test Utils, Pytest, Supertest.

Experience

May 2020 - Present

Senior Software Developer

Emumba Private Limited.

- · Work with an Agile based team committed to deliver software with high standards in short time.
- Participate in team discussions related to design and architecture of products/features.
- Develop high quality, fast and maintainable software using test driven development and following design patterns and industry practices.
- · Refactoring code and writing tests for existing functionality to increase coverage.
- Participate in pair programming to increase productivity and knowledge of team members.
- Mentor junior developers and conduct technical interviews to identify talented candidates.
- Participate in on-call rotation to ensure the availability & reliability of services and tackle operational issues & customer-impacting outages.

Aug 2019 - May 2020

Senior Software Developer

Auxilio Tech

- Worked as a technical platform lead of a small team responsible for delivering company's flagship product.
- Participated in architecture and design related discussions.
- Implemented a number of critical areas of the application both on front end and back end.
- Participated in task specifications, breakdown and assignment.
- Participated in code review activity to ensure high code quality.
- Coordinated with Software Quality Assurance Engineers to ensure high-quality deliverables.

Mar 2016 - Aug 2019

Software Developer

AbbVie Inc.

- Worked as a developer in company's core technology team for delivering high quality Workflow Automation solutions.
- Efficiently collaborated with the team in designing and implementing productive solutions for workflow automation that replaced existing inefficient implementations.
- Improved system performance by making proactive adjustments and resolving bugs.
- Worked on improving the code coverage by writing unit tests.

Education

Aug 2011 - May 2015

Bachelors of Science(Computer Science)

National University of Computer & Emerging Sciences, Islamabad